The vermin traitor has finally died, eh?
(ゼツ)裏切り者の虫ケラが
やっと死んだか。
He was vermin...
and persistent as a cockroach.
(ゼツ)虫ケラは 虫ケラでも
このしつこさは ゴキブリだったな。
ハハハハハ！
Don't laugh at Obito!
(ナルト)オビトを笑うな。
Naruto...
(サクラ)ナルト…。
If you keep resisting,
ナルト… お前も
これ以上 刃向かってると→
you'll end up pitifully crumbling
to ash just like him!
崩れて灰になった
哀れでみじめなそいつと→
As someone who tried to
become Hokage,
同じになるんだ。
火影になろうとしたオビトは
俺には…。
Obito is...
... nothing but awesome to me!
なっ！
かっこよくしか見えねえよ！
No way!
バカな！
I can't move!
《くっ！ 動けん》
I don't even have
much strength left,
and yet, I was left behind again?
《カカシ : たいした力もないくせに
また 残されたということか》
Are you all right, Rin?
Kakashi?
((オビト : 大丈夫か？ リン… カカシ…。
Obito!
(カカシ)オビト！
Don't...
It's okay, Kakashi.
(オビト)やめろ。 いいんだ カカシ。
I don't think I can make it...
俺は もう ダメみたいだ。
My right side is totally crushed.
体の右側は
ほとんど潰れちまって→
I can't even feel anything...
感覚すら ねえ…。
Damn it!
(カカシ)クソ！
I'm giving you my Sharingan.
この俺の写輪眼をやるからよ。
Whatever the village may say...
里のやつらが なんて言おうと
お前は 立派な上忍だ。
you are... a great jonin.
That's how I really feel...
それが 俺の気持だ。
So please accept it.
(受け取ってくれ))
Kakashi...
((リン : カカシ…))
– Rin!
((リン！
リン！
Again, you...
《オビト : キミは また…》
Thank you, Rin.
《ありがとう リン。
Obito and I will be
joining you shortly.
俺も オビトも
そろそろ そっちへ行くよ。
We can catch up then,
the three of us together...
また ３人で
ゆっくり話をしよう》
Rin...
This time, let's...
《リン… 今度は あの世で→
spend some alone time together.
Just you and me...
少し 俺と
２人きりの時間を過ごそう》
Kakashi would just be in the way.
I'll leave him here.
《カカシは邪魔だ。
ここに置いていくよ》
This is... Kamui!
これは… 神威!?
Obito! You!
オビト… お前！
Kakashi...
you stay here a little while longer.
カカシ… お前は 当分 こっちにいろ。
Don't you rush to follow us!
(すぐに来んじゃねえぞ))
Why, Obito?
What am I even here for?
《なぜだ!? オビト！
俺は なんのために…》
aimaina hyouden koshiraete hitatteru no
I create a vague critical biography and wallow in it
seisei saisai nani o mada matteru no
Generation after generation, time after time,
what are you still waiting for
itsunomanika hitori ni natta
I was all alone before I knew it
tameiki hitotsu haite nageite
Breathed out a single sigh and lamented
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosunda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
en de tsunagareba kono hibi mo
Bind these days with bonds and perhaps
suteru hodo koware tenaidarou
They can be salvaged
ayumi o tomenaide
Don't stop walking forward
kibou o sutenaide
Don't give up hope
douka furimuite
Please look back
dou ka kimiyo
Please, if you would
jin jin kokoro ga itamunara
If the heart throbs with pain
kannen no ori o uchiyaburu nda
Break through the ideology that imprisons you
enen tsukihi wa megurukedo
Time goes around for eternity
suteru ni wa yami ga asaidarou
But the darkness within you is still shallow,
not worth throwing it all away
jounetsu moyashita ano koro o
Those days of burning passion
shinketsu sosoide torimodosu nda
Put your heart and soul into getting them back
ai o wakeaeba kono hibi mo
If we love each other then surely these days will
mouichido kimi o terasudarou
Once again, shine upon you
The Sharingan
Revived
This is embarrassing...
Screwing up like that in front of you.
ヘヘ まいったよな。
いきなり かっこ悪いとこ
見せちまって。
It looks like
you've calmed down a bit.
少しは落ち着いたみたいだね。
Okay, Obito.
Rin, do you mind waiting
just a bit longer?
さぁ オビト。
リン もう少しだけ
待ってくれないか？
Obito?
Only a little bit before
we move on...
オビト？
あの世にいく間
ほんの少しでいい→
I'd like to make one more
detour along the way.
もう少し遠回りしていきたいんだ。
Who do you want to save this time?
もう 今度は誰を助けたいの？
Kakashi.
I've finally gotten alone time with you.
カカシだ。
It'll be wasted if he ends up
coming here right away.
やっと リンと
２人きりになれたんだ。
すぐ あいつに
来られちゃ台なしだ。
Besides... He's out there helpless.
それに あいつが何もできないで
はたけに突っ立ってる→
Just like his namesake, he's a scarecrow
in the middle of a garden...
文字どおりの
カカシみたいになってるのは→
And I'm sort of annoyed by it.
何か シャクなんだ。
Despite all that's happened,
you two are still close, huh?
フフフ いろいろあったけど→
N-No way!
やっぱり仲がいいんだね。
We're oil and water!
そ そんなことねえよ
あいつと俺は水と油だ。
So?
You can go just like that?
フフ それで すぐにいけるの？
Yeah...
Chakra is an energy
that connects two worlds.
ああ チャクラってのは→
I'm gonna go see Kakashi!
２つの世界をつなげる力だ。
カカシに会ってくるよ。
I'll be waiting right here.
Sorry, Rin!
I'll be right back!
ここで待ってる。
悪いな リン すぐ戻ってくっからな。
Obito?!
Before I go to the next world,
I thought I'd emphasize to you...
(カカシ)オビト!?
あの世にいく前に
お前がこっちに来ないよう→
to not to come
running after me so quickly.
念押ししておこうと思ってよ。
Besides, it's going to
keep bothering me
if this eye I gave you to
celebrate your promotion to jonin,
せっかく上忍祝いのプレゼントで
この目をやったのに→
came back to me.
それが帰ってきたんじゃ
寝覚めが悪くてよ。
Obito, you...
Then again, it's not like I'll be
springing back to life anymore.
オビト お前…。
つっても もうこの世で
目覚めることもないんだが。
More importantly,
you know how I told Naruto
to become Hokage?
そんなことより
俺は さっき ナルトに→
I meant to say as the Seventh.
火影になれっつったんだけどよ。
ただ そりゃ 七代目だ。
You be the Sixth Hokage, Kakashi.
六代目火影は お前がなれ カカシ。
I know you haven't taken office yet,
but I'm giving you your gift now.
まだ就任したわけじゃないが
祝いのプレゼントを先にやっとくよ。
It has a fixed time limit,
but it isn't useless.
期限付きだが
役に立たないものじゃない。
Do you get what I'm saying?
I mean... you haven't forgotten
your famous nickname
わかってるよな？
that's known throughout
the lands, have you?
そもそも他国にまで
とどろかせた自分の勇名を→
忘れちゃいないだろ？
That name, Kakashi of the Sharingan!
(オビト)写輪眼のカカシって名を。
(サスケ)ハァッ！
Let's do this, guys!
《いくぞ みんな！》
Mmhm.
(守鶴)フン。
Yes!
Yup!
(又旅)はい。
(磯撫)うん。
All right!
Roger.
(孫悟空)よっしゃ。
Sure thing!
(穆王)了解。
Gotcha!
(犀犬)あいよ。
Yeah!
Here we go!
(重明)わかった。
(牛鬼)おう。
(九喇嘛)やるぞ。
Sage Art: Super Tailed Beast
Rasen-Shuriken!
仙法 超尾獣螺旋手裏剣！
そりゃ～！
Nice, Naruto!
ナイス ナルト！
There's no way they can
come out of that unscathed.
《あれをくらったら さすがに
無傷じゃいられないはず》
ううっ！
う～！
Oh no! Don't tell me Mother's—!
《まさか 母さん ここで!?》
What's that?
なんなの？
She turned into
another gigantic thing?
また… デケエのに なんだ？
What is that?
A wolf? Tanuki?
狼？ 狸？ ムジナ？
Badger? Or a rabbit?
It doesn't matter.
Now it's easier to get close.
うさぎか？
なんでもいい。
And it'll be easier to seal her!
これで近づきやすくなった
封印もしやすくなる！
It's not... humanoid?
《これは人型じゃない。
Mother didn't transform into
Ten Tails of her own will.
母さんの意思で
十尾化したんじゃないぞ。
Are the Tailed Beasts
within her resonating
さっきのナルトの攻撃に
尾獣どもが呼応して→
in response to Naruto's attack
and starting to split apart?
They're not stable!
分離しかかって
いるんじゃないのか？
安定していない！》
ギャー！
Sasuke, don't get grabbed
by that white hand!
It will absorb you instantly!
サスケ あの白い手に つかまんな。
And it's fast too!
一瞬で取り込まれちまうぞ。
I know that!
しかも速え！
わかってる！
ああ！
Sasuke!
Protect Sakura with
your Visual Prowess!
サスケ お前の瞳術で
サクラちゃんを！
All right, way to go!
A Susano'o?! Whose was it?
よっしゃ やったぜ！
須佐能乎 誰だ？
W-What? That wasn't you?!
って ええ？
お前じゃねえのかよ！
What's going on?!
《クッ どういうことだ？》
Kakashi Sensei!
Thank you... Obito.
(サクラ)カカシ先生？
《オビト ありがとう》
That's impossible. No way!
Sure it is!
バカな そんなはずが…。
We are talking about the Copy Ninja,
Kakashi of the Sharingan!
おかしかねえだろ。
コピー忍者 写輪眼のカカシ
っていうぐらいだからな。
But he shouldn't have
the Sharingan anymore...
先生ってば！
もう 写輪眼は
持っていないはずだが。
I don't get it, but he saved me!
よくわからないけど
助かった。
You watch along with me.
This time, I'll protect them...
《お前も一緒に見ていてくれ。
今度こそ あいつらを
世界を守る！》
and the world!
Here it comes!
来たぞ！
うわ！
How about this?
Combining the power
of the Kamui into...
shuriken!
《これならどうだ！
神威の力を 手裏剣に！》
Kamui Shuriken!
神威手裏剣！
Just as I thought...
Gaining Six Path's power enhances
one's Visual Prowess too!
思ったとおりだ。
六道の力を得ていたぶん
瞳力が上がっている。
This power...
It's Obito's Sharingan?
But why does
Kakashi Sensei have it?
《この力 オビトの写輪眼？
それが なんでカカシ先生に？》
Wow!
That's more amazing
than yours, Sasuke!
おお サスケのより すげえ！
This chakra is—!
《このチャクラは…》
This Root Time-Space is
Mother's exclusive domain,
where she can
directly extract chakra
(ゼツ)無限月読の忍たちから
チャクラを直接抽出できる→
from shinobi trapped in
the Infinite Tsukuyomi!
この始球空間こそ
母さんの特別領域。
The Tailed Beasts are now stable,
and Mother has even produced
a Truthseeker Orb...
尾獣どもは すでに安定し→
An Expansive Kekkei Moura
Truthseeker Orb
更には
母さんの求道玉まで出した。
that contains
each and every nature...
風火土雷水 陰陽
すべての性質を合わせた→
Wind, fire, earth, lightning,
water, shadow, and light.
It is the beginning of
a new Time-Space.
血継網羅の膨張求道玉。
And you all will
become its sacrifice!
新たな空間の始まりだ。
お前らは その犠牲となるのだ。
That thing!
It's the same sphere
as the one behind me!
こりゃ… 俺の後ろのと同じ玉だ。
The difference in size is too drastic!
And it's growing rapidly!
大きさが違いすぎるだろ。
I definitely can't teleport away such
a gigantic object with the Kamui.
それに
どんどん大きくなってるぞ。
(カカシ)さすがに
あれほど大きなものを→
Even if we get out of this Time-Space
and escape temporarily...
神威で飛ばせない。
俺たちが時空間に飛んで
いったん逃げたとしても→
If that thing becomes too big,
we won't be able to return here.
あれが大きくなりすぎれば
当然 もう戻ってこられなくなる。
In order to stop that...
We need to seal
that Rabbit Granny away right now!
あれを止めるには…。
本体のうさぎババアを 今すぐ
封印するしかねえってことだ。
You're right.
Gather 'round. I've got a plan.
だよね。
集まれ 作戦を伝える。
This will be our last mission
as the former Squad 7!
これが俺たち 元第７班としての
最後の任務だ。
We're going to save the world!
Yeah!
俺たちで世界を救うぞ。
フン。
Roger!
I am immortal.
おう！
了解！
If either of you die,
you cannot seal me away.
(カグヤ)わらわは不死。
どちらか一方が死ねば
封印はできぬ。
Now then...
さて…。
Which shall it be?
You're mine, damn it!
どちらにする？
No, we attack her together.
俺が相手だ この野郎！
She's scared of being sealed
and her attention will be divided!
いや 一緒に攻める。
やつは封印を恐れ
注意力が二分される。
Take me part of the way.
Then I'll fly the rest of the way.
Right!
途中まで連れていけ あとは跳ぶ。
おう。
So fast!
Mother just gained more power.
《速い！》
Both her power and speed
are now exponentially greater!
《母さんは力を得たばかり。
威力もスピードも
段違いになってんのさ》
Being able to pass through things,
really is a handy ability, Obito...
《やはり… いい能力だな オビト。
And now, I can resurrect this move too!
すり抜けるのは…。
そして この技も復活だ》
Kamui Lightning Blade!
《神威雷切！》
Mother!
This is bad!
Her right arm!
くっ！
母さん！
《ゼツ : まずい 右手が…》
There's not enough time to escape
into another Time-Space!
《別空間の中へ逃げるにも
空間を広げる時間がない。
Then!
なら！》
ぐぁっ！
So they were both
Ashura's reincarnates, after all.
《やはり どちらもアシュラの転生者。
They must have,
switched back then.
あのとき すでに変化していたか。
So then, the one on the right
is the real one!
そして… 右が本物！》
Kamui!
神威！
Not good.
《まずい…》
I'll go to the Ice World...
No...
The Indra reincarnate
possesses the Amaterasu...
《氷の空間へ。
いや インドラの転生者には天照が…。
That wouldn't be good!
それは ダメだ！》
Don't forget about me!
We're both women...
so don't mock me!
《私だっているんだ。
同じ女なら バカにしないで！》
Naruto... Sasuke... Sakura!
なっ…。
《ナルト サスケ サクラ…》
((ニシシッ。
A silly prank...
Still, if this prank
was the result of teamwork...
《カカシ : ベタなイタズラか。
だが イタズラもチームワークがあるなら…》
He fell for it!
ハハハハハッ！
引っかかった 引っかかった。
So Naruto's the perp.
I'm so sorry, Sensei.
I tried to stop him, but Naruto...
《カカシ : 仕掛けたのは ナルト》
先生 ごめんなさい。
私は とめたんですが ナルト君が。
Sakura makes excuses
and tries to protect herself.
《カカシ : サクラは言い訳 自身の保身。
Sasuke minds his own business.
He probably doesn't
consider them comrades.
サスケは我関せず。
仲間とすら思っていないようだな。
There's not
a shred of teamwork...
チームワークのカケラもなしか…》
How do I put this...
My first impression of you guys
is not good!
(カカシ)ん～ なんて言うのかな。
I'll go! I'll go!
お前らの第一印象は 嫌いだ。
I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
I love instant ramen.
俺さ 俺さ 名前は うずまきナルト。
But I love the ramen at Ichiraku that
Iruka Sensei treats me to even more!
好きなものは カップラーメン。
もっと好きなもんは
イルカ先生におごってもらった→
And I hate having to wait three minutes
after pouring in the hot water.
一楽のラーメン！
嫌いなものは
お湯をいれてからの３分間。
My future dream is...
to surpass the Hokage!
将来の夢は… 火影を超す！
And that's why
I'm going to make everyone in
the village acknowledge me!
んでもって 里のやつら全員に
俺の存在を認めさせてやるんだ。
My name is Sasuke Uchiha.
I have lots of dislikes,
名は うちはサスケ。
but no likes in particular.
嫌いなものなら たくさんあるが
好きなものは別にない。
And I don't feel like summing up
my ambition as just a dream,
それから 夢なんて言葉で
終わらす気はないが→
but I do have an ambition.
The ambition to restore my clan
and to kill a certain man without fail!
野望はある。
一族の復興と
ある男を必ず… 殺すことだ。
I'm Sakura Haruno.
What I like...
I mean, who I like is...
私は 春野サクラ。
好きなものは… ってゆ～か！
好きな人は… え～と…。
My future dream is...
将来の夢も言っちゃおうかな。
キャーッ！
They're all wrapped up
in themselves.
They're far from
working together as a team.
どいつもこいつも 見事にバラバラ。
チームワークとは 程遠いな。
Although we were just like that...
俺らも似たようなものだったが。
Oh well, I'll just have
to do what I can.
(まぁ やるだけやってみるさ))
Yup... You guys make
a pretty picture right now.
《うん いい画だ。
今のお前らは…》
Now!
Shannaro!
All right!
今だ！
しゃ～んなろ～！
よっしゃ！
I really love you guys!
(カカシ)大好きだ。
boku ni wa wakaru nda uso o tsuite iru kimi ga
I can tell when you're lying
naite ii yo koko ni zutto irukara
It's okay to cry because I'll always be here
sekaijuu ni koborete iru hontou no ai no kimochi
Feelings of true love spills out throughout the world
sagashidashite miushinatte yoake ga kuru no matteru
We search for it but lose it, while waiting for daybreak
migi no hoshi ni wa boku no namae o tsukete
The star on the right will bear my name
kimi ga yonde okureyo
Will you call out to it?
hidari no hoshi ni wa kimi no namae ga ne
The star on the left will bear your name
niau yo zutto soba ni irukara
It's perfect, because we'll always be together
We finally made it out!
Kurama!
Your Jinchuriki sure gets it done!
Now it's happily ever after!
Yeah!
Hold on a sec!
What about us?
How are we supposed to
get out of this Time-Space?
Oh, you're right!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Congratulations"
But... he's still pretty dumb,
isn't he?